Guide to the Merion Bluegrass Association Records 1957-1991
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Merion Bluegrass Association records
1957-1991
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Merion Bluegrass Association
Cage 867
2.45 linear feet of shelf space 6 boxes
The Merion Bluegrass Association Records consists of correspondence, by-laws, financial statements, budgets, minutes, annual meeting materials, membership rosters, photographs, and advertising material from the Merion Bluegrass Association up until its dissolution in 1989.
Historical Note
In 1954 Arden Jacklin, George Royes and Dwight Hopkins incorporated the Merion Blue Grass Association in Oregon. The purpose of the Association was to promote, advertise and educate the public in the "use and desirable features of" Merion Blue Grass, thereby increasing its consumption. The Association was a non-profit organization. It met annually in Oregon or Washington to discuss and further its business, and conducted public relations through an office in New York. The Merion Bluegrass Association was dissolved in 1989. The balance of the Association's funds were donated to the Ralph Engel Turfgrass Scholarship Fund at Rutgers University.
This collection contains records of the Merion Bluegrass Association. The collection consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence, financial reports, by-laws, meeting minutes and committee reports, and papers pertaining to membership, public relations, and research and development. Additionally the collection contains material relating to the dissolution of the Merion Bluegrass Association in 1989, including IRS documents. The collection also includes advertisements and advertising research files, turf grass pamphlets, Lawn Institute material, photographs, film negatives, and a slideshow with narration (33 1/2 rpm disc).
The documents in this collection are arranged in five series: administrative, correspondence, research, financial, and promotion and events.
Series 1: Administrative, 1957-1989. This series contains material on the operation of the Merion Bluegrass Association. This includes meeting minutes, meeting files, board meetings, by-laws, and membership applications. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series 2: Correspondence, 1978-1991. This series contains all correspondence material including correspondence with members, their public relations firm, and researchers, notably C. Reed Funk at Rutgers University. Also present is a mailing list. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series 3: Research, 1970-1991. This series contains research and statistical data. Included are turf grass pamphlets and Rutgers University research correspondence material. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series 4: Financial, 1979-1990. This series contains all financial material, including financial reports and Internal Revenue Service material that detail the dissolution of the Merion Bluegrass Association in 1989. This series is arranged chronologically.
Series 5: Promotions and Events, 1961-1988. This series contains advertising material including flyers and brochures. Also included is a lawn and turf benefits pamphlet, photographs, and slide show with accompanying narration in the form of a vinyl record. This series is arranged alphabetically.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Donated to Washington State University on behalf of the Merion Bluegrass Association in 1991 (MS.1991.59).
Merion Bluegrass Association Records 1954-1982 (Cage 528)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Merion Bluegrass Association -- Archives.
Agriculture -- Northwest, Pacific -- Societies, etc. -- Records and correspondence; Bluegrasses
Agriculture; Washington (State)
- Administrative, 1957-1989; Series 1
  - Richard Bailey, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letterhead material, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting files, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clifford Mattila files, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting files, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership applications, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership program, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Merion Bluegrass by-laws, 1957-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1978-1991; Series 2
  - Margaret Herbst Public Relations, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Member correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Merion Bluegrass mailing list, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Eveson, Snyder, Lincoln and Company, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lawn Institute, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Margaret Herbst Public Relations, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Member correspondence, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Merion Bluegrass mailing list, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Research, 1970-1991; Series 3
  - Research, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Research and development, 1970-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Research and development, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Research and development committee, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Rutgers Turfgrass Proceedings, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Rutgers University, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Rutgers University, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Statistical, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 30-31)
  - Statistics, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Turfgrass evaluation programs, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Turfgrass variety lists, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Financial, 1979-1990; Series 4
  - Financial, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Financial reports, 1983-1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Promotions and events, 1961-1988; Series 5
  - 1978-1979 Promotion, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 6th Annual Turf Field Day, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Flyers and brochures, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Lawn and Sports Turf Benefits, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Lawn Institute Outreach, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Photographs, 1980-1987 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Slide show, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Slide show narration, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)